<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Ali Yagiz Dizdaroglu</title>
    <link>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Ali Yagiz Dizdaroglu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Data Assets for Ivy ML framework</title>
      <link>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_iv/</guid>
      <description>In this grand project I attempted to dive into Ivy&amp;rsquo;s world of AI! This was a joyful of journey that I met new peoples and systems. My responsibility was to implement and format data assets and functions. Though I had to confront various exciting technical situations which had been a great experience-dense boost to me!
github link:
https://github.com/unifyai/ivy/pull/1945</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell Segmentation and Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_ii/</guid>
      <description>This project consists of 2 different solutions to the expected results:
statistics.csv (cell characteristics and feature analysis) layered/masked images Solution 1, Manual Trained Model:
Chose a pretty common and robust DL algorithm/model named &amp;ldquo;U-net&amp;rdquo; which is a CNN type. Had to resize the images to 768x768 because of RAM issues. Then converted to original size forming pieces of small images. Size re-conversion is a bit scuffed. For details please see the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Price Prediction</title>
      <link>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_iii/</guid>
      <description>The Ames Housing dataset was compiled by Dean De Cock for use in data science education. It&amp;rsquo;s an incredible alternative for data scientists looking for a modernized and expanded version of the often cited Boston Housing dataset. The data split in two-part train and test. The training dataset has target value (home price), the test set doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a target value and it needs to be predicted.
My progression:
Data cleaning Feature engineering Regressor selection (XGBoost) Parameter tuning Auto ML attempt Visualization Results github link:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Classification via Twitter</title>
      <link>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_i/</guid>
      <description>Steps conducted:
Text data acquisition using Twitter APIs for a week Preparation of training data Data preprocessing and cleaning Research to find the optimal algorithm in order to classify Eventually decided on Supervised Learning and Naive Bayes Multiclass Classification under 5 distinct categories Obtained 85% accuracy on classification for over 10,000 tweets Abstract:
Data science and particularly data itself have been a core part of living all along throughout human history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetical Data Analytics</title>
      <link>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_v/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AliYagizDizdaroglu.github.io/Ali_Portfolio/post/project_v/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Days to death prediction After the &amp;ldquo;txt to csv&amp;rdquo; data wrangling process:
Common procedures throughout 2 models(XGBoost, RandomForest):
dropping demographic_id as it is unique to person and no use for us
dropping age_at_diagnosis, we have the same as days_to_birth
changing paper_clinical_stage to number respectively (1,2,3,4)
changing vital_status to number respectively (0,1)
finding current age = days_to_birth / -365.24
had to convert to int indirectly (&amp;ldquo;vital_status&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;paper_clinical_stage&amp;rdquo;)
dropping dead with unknown year_of_death as it makes no sense</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
